PATTIA CLUB
I do not believe that my dream
is just an illusion,
that there is no karma in this world.
If the ocean is meant to spill,
let the water of misery fill my heart.
If far away I must go,
the storms I must weather.
All for freedom.
By Xu Meng.
What a shocker.
All these smoke and mirrors
in superstition.
In the end, it was all to run away
from debt collectors.
We should be more rational.
What's wrong?
We solved the case. Why the long face?
I'm wondering if this is the only answer.
How many answers do you need?
Even in a comic book,
they always say there's only one truth.
What is going on? A grand reception?
Captain.
WEIYANG PUBLIC SECURITY BUREAU
NANSHAN BRANCH
Let's go.
Captain Feng.
What's going on?
You two solved a big case today.
-We solved a case?
-How did you know we solved the case?
I haven't even told you about it yet.
Didn't you ask me
to ambush the pickpocket?
He did see a briefcase
with Qingsong Cement written on it.
It was hidden inside Wu Shanlong's house.
What was inside?
Photocopies of the tender document
on Dongshan Mine.
Does it mean the case is solved now?
Wu Shanlong was the whistle-blower.
Song Qingsong paid Director Li of the mine
eight million yuan to win the bid.
Director Li sure is cunning.
He wants the best of both worlds.
He sold the tender
to both Song Qingsong and Cripple Du.
And in the end, they fought.
I get it now. Director Li
conducted this whole farce.
He said someone stole
the tender document from the mine.
In reality, he was
just diverting attention.
Exactly.
Sir. We have good news too.
Is it about
the missing father and daughter?
They disappeared on purpose.
We have evidence.
Good things come in pairs.
When I see the chief next time,
I'll put in a good word for you two.
Sir. There's no rush for that.
But my secondment ends tomorrow.
I have to return to the police station.
About my secondment evaluation report…
Oh, He Yuanhang.
You're crafty.
Well, I have to bring something back
for that green-eyed colleague of mine.
Before you return tomorrow,
bring me the case summary report,
and you'll have your evaluation report.
Captain Feng, do I
have to write the report too?
The quality of your report
will affect the quality of mine.
What?
All the best.
But… Captain Feng.
Tomorrow? I've stayed up late
for a few nights already.
He. Go back and rest up.
I'll write the report.
It's okay.
Working late is part and parcel
of being a criminal detective.
You know what? Go back and sleep.
Drop by my place tomorrow
at noon to check my report.
You can also taste my wife's cooking.
-She'll make noodles for you. See you.
-Okay.
-Drive safely!
Help yourself.
Sir,
I no longer eat coriander.
you're now retired.
Xiaohe has also grown up.
Why don't you just enjoy your retirement?
Are you telling me to give up?
No.
I'm telling you to accept
your current pace
and you may continue to be useful.
That's just giving up.
Back then, you told me
to let it go when it was time to do so
instead of dwelling on it.
Otherwise, we would…
Sir.
Don't visit Yuanlongli anymore.
I wanted to retire too back then.
But you had to drag me in.
Now, it's the other way round.
Ran Fangxu.
Just be frank with me.
Are you going to pretend
for the rest of your life
that the June 30th case never happened?
I made a wrong call back then.
That was on me.
But it has been 18 years now.
We've gone through every lead we had.
There are no new leads.
No new leads?
Come here.
-Sir.
-Come here.
No new leads?
No new leads? What is this?
What is this?
What are these if not new leads?
Sir!
Why else do you think
I always visit Yuanlongli?
Because I know
it has the most important lead.
As long as Yuanlongli is still here,
the case can be solved.
Let it go already, sir.
No need to waste your life on one case.
I can't! Just go away then.
I'll just investigate it myself.
Sir.
Sir!
YUANLONGLI INTERNATIONAL GARDEN
MISSING PERSON
Sir, what are you doing? Stop posting it.
If you can insist on quitting,
let me insist on investigating as well.
We have nothing to do with each other.
Your posters serve no purpose, sir.
Just come back with me.
Sir.
Many things don't come with answers.
I don't want answers.
I want the truth.
Let go. Let go of me.
No!
I won't unless you come back.
I don't need you now. Let go.
-No.
-Let…
Who's there?
Dad? What are you doing?
Xiaohe.
Xiaohe. Don't leave.
Look. We're already here anyway.
Maybe you, Uncle Ran, and I
can investigate this case together.
I can't monitor you all the time.
I can't chain you to a post.
I can't stop you.
Whenever I go out,
you sneak into Yuanlongli.
What if you fall sick again?
Sick? Look at me.
The very picture of health.
Dad. I have work to do. Please
go back with Uncle Ran.
She's right.
-Let's go, sir.
-Shut up.
Xiaohe.
You're here to find evidence
to appeal against
Han Zi'ang's expulsion, aren't you?
Since Uncle Ran and I are here,
we can assist you.
I don't need your help.
Our investigation skills are exceptional.
I don't need you.
I can swear. I can swear
that if we fail to find anything useful,
we will leave right away.
We won't disturb you when you work.
What… What
can you two do anyway?
Right?
I have no idea either.
Don't play dumb.
You know what?
Take… Take the helmet for me.
Stay here. Don't move. Come. Follow me.
Where are you going?
Just stay there. Don't move.
MISSING PERSONS
He Xiaohe. How can you believe
the words of a madman?
-Run! Quick.
-What's going on?
Quick! Quick!
-It's dangerous. Move aside.
-Who's chasing after you?
Careful.
Dad! Who's pursuing you?
-Careful.
-Dad!
Dad!
What are you trying to do?
Who is pursuing you?
Re-enactment is so effective.
Dad. Can you stop messing around?
This is called a re-enactment.
It's Uncle Ran's expertise.
Re-enactment?
Put yourself in the shoes of Han Zi'ang
and re-enact what he did.
Then, find clues during the process.
You're saying
that Han Zi'ang wasn't lying in ambush.
Someone was pursuing him.
That was why he hid in the cupboard.
Where's your proof?
Uncle Ran is back. He'll answer you.
No need for that.
Xiaohe is smart enough
to deduce it herself.
Did you get it then?
Help!
Help! Help!
I hear a ghost.
Where is it?
Over there.
Han Zi'ang might have
been assaulted first.
Then, he fled.
Fearing assault,
he acted out of self-defense
after he hid in the cupboard.
Xiaohe.
This is your logical deduction.
You'll have to find the evidence yourself.
Understood?
You have to rely on yourself.
Sir. You've seen how Xiaohe did just now.
Yes.
It exceeded my expectations.
I know she is a capable officer,
and I can't wait to see her
solve this case.
Are you saying
that you still want to quit?
Sir,
I will wait for Xiaohe's
good news in Beijing.
Then, I'll insert this case
into my teaching material.
You're going back to Beijing?
Yes.
Dad.
It'll be dawn soon.
Uncle Ran has to catch the train.
Let's go. I'll give you
a lift to the train station.
Okay.
AWARDED TO HE YUANHANG
OUTSTANDING POLICE OFFICER
OF NANSHAN DISTRICT
…THE STORMS I MUST WEATHER
ALL FOR FREEDOM. XU MENG
YUANLONGLI JUNE 30TH CASE, SUMMARY REPORT
On August 24th, 1995,
Xu Zhihong, father, and Xu Meng, daughter,
were involved in an accident on Mount Wu.
Xu Zhihong suffered severe injuries
-What's the matter?
-and had to seek
long-term medical treatment.
Dad!
Dad! Dad!
Save my dad. He fainted.
Save my dad. Save my dad.
Xu Meng pawned her assets
and took out loans
to pay for her father's medical bills.
IOU, XU MENG
Didn't you say 8,000 yuan?
How come there's only 6,000 yuan?
You think I don't need
the handling fee? Huh?
Don't just stand there.
-Pay up now! Pay up!
-Pay up now!
-Pay up!
-Pay up now! Pay up!
-Pay up now!
-Pay up!
As the Xus accumulated debts,
-debt collectors visited them more often.
-Pay up!
They shouted threats,
pushing the victims into desperation.
-Pay up!
-Yes, pay up!
-Pay up, Xu Meng!
-Xu Meng!
-I know you're in there.
-Just come
after me, you punks!
Old cripple, come out now.
-Get out now!
-Don't harass my daughter!
-If you can stay in there,
-Stay put.
-come out and pay up now.
-It's okay.
-Pay up!
-Bullying a girl now?
-Come out now!
-Are you even men?
Our investigation
indicates that Xu Meng
defrauded many people
by repeatedly mortgaging her property.
They had the motive to run away
from their debt collectors and pursuers.
Mengmeng,
death
is
our only solution.
Dad,
I don't want to die.
Let's run away, okay?
We'll disappear in Weiyang.
Vanishing in Weiyang
became their only way out.
According to the testimony
of Du Mandun, a Yuanlongli resident,
Xu Meng visited the New York Block
to devise her escape route
before she executed her plan.
Elevators are operated
by the same generic key.
Having worked in Dajianchang
for many years,
Xu Zhihong was familiar
with tools and could make keys.
Additionally, the Xus
also picked the date carefully.
They opted for a day when the residents
would be watching the reunification
of Hong Kong broadcast.
The absence of people on the street
facilitated their escape plan.
At around 4:30 p.m., June 30th,
Xu Meng carried Xu Zhihong on her back
and arrived at Yuanlongli.
At 4:38 p.m.,
Xu Meng and Xu Zhihong
took the elevator to the 18th floor.
Before they exited the elevator,
Xu Zhihong pressed all the buttons
in the elevator.
After they left the elevator,
they split up.
When the elevator stopped briefly
on the 17th floor,
Xu Meng went to 1813
and hung the black cloak.
Xu Zhihong then unlocked
the door to the elevator shaft.
They worked together
and dragged two wooden planks
with their footprints
to the top of the elevator.
Preliminary analysis shows
that Xu Meng's and Xu Zhihong's
footprints, handprints
collected on the elevator roof,
and even the handwriting in the letter,
match the ones collected
in their place of residence.
Dad. We must live on.
Don't be scared.
When the elevator stopped
on the first floor,
the Xus unlocked
the elevator door from the shaft
and arrived at the lobby
on the second floor.
They took the eastern staircase
and headed to B1.
It is connected
to the underground car park.
When Xu Meng worked in Pattia,
she got her hands on the keys
to the underground car park.
YUANLONGLI UNDERGROUND PARKING LOT
They took the car park exit
and left Yuanlongli.
That route was not covered
by security cameras.
The Xus mystified their disappearance
so that rumors would spread.
The superstitious beliefs
would also deter their debt collectors
from coming closer,
thereby giving up on pursuing them.
In conclusion,
this is a premeditated, voluntary
missing person case motivated
by the desire to evade debt collection.
Should any request to locate them be made,
we recommend requesting the city council
to enlarge the search scope.
WRITTEN BY, TIME
Written by Ran Fangxu,
He Yuanhang.
WRITTEN BY: RAN FANGXU, HE YUANHANG
TIME: JULY 5TH, 1997
Hi, Uncle Ran.
-Hi, Xiaohe.
-You're here.
Allow me to introduce him.
Ran. R-A-N.
Ran Fangxu.
And this one is my wife,
Sun Yun. Director Sun.
-Hi, Mrs. He.
-Hi, Ran.
-This is for you.
-You didn't have to.
Come in. Let me serve the noodles.
Take the shoes.
-Uncle Ran, your sandals.
-Thank you, Xiaohe. This is for you.
What is that?
Oh. A doll.
Thank you, Uncle Ran.
They both have something. Is this mine?
A freebie when I bought
the gift for your wife.
A freebie? I like it.
It suits me.
Come. Come.
Here.
Take a seat.
Make sure you don't tell my wife later
that I'm going back to the police station.
But aren't you going back tomorrow?
-You haven't told your wife?
-The noodles are ready.
Come.
How nice.
Listen. My wife cooked
a whole table of food for you.
Sorry for the hassle, Mrs. He.
Not a hassle at all. Take a seat.
Okay.
It smells divine.
Dad told me
Uncle Ran likes coriander best.
I washed them all myself.
Thank you, Xiaohe.
Come. Let's have a toast.
-Welcome to our humble abode, Ran.
-Thank you, Mrs. He.
-You're welcome.
-Welcome.
He Yuanhang.
Are you hiding something from me?
Why would I be hiding something from you?
Didn't you say Ran was your apprentice?
So isn't it a bit inappropriate for him
to call me Mrs. He?
It sounds younger that way.
Madam Sun sounds way older.
Lie. Lie more.
Ran is a top scorer from PPSUC.
You're here for a secondment.
There's no way he's your apprentice.
Right, Ran?
He
is indeed my mentor.
Did you hear that?
Feng did this?
-Eat more.
-Thank you, Mrs. He.
You can hardly find a down-to-earth
young man nowadays.
You're smart, capable,
and have the required qualification.
I'm sure your workplace
will invest a lot in you.
He will stay at the criminal department.
Ran, you will support him, won't you?
Actually, the criminal department
has a heavy workload.
Even heavier than a bank.
Xiaohe is still young.
She needs her parents.
Yes, Dad.
I need my parents.
For what?
The biggest thing a father can do
for his children
is to be a great role model,
not to keep them company.
Don't you agree, Ran?
Yes. You're right.
Oh, Ran.
Are you single?
I know many single women in my work.
Do you want me to introduce
some of them to you?
Uncle Ran doesn't need that.
I know Ms. Qiao.
She likes Uncle Ran.
She's so pretty.
Where does she work? She's quick.
Mrs. He.
I just arrived in Weiyang.
I just want to focus on my work.
I don't have time for anything else.
Sir.
How did the case report go?
Oh. It's almost done.
But I'm not so sure about certain details.
Can you help me?
-You can read it after the meal.
-It won't take long. Work comes first.
Come. Take a look.
We'll be back soon. Soon.
Stop playing with it. Eat.
SHE LEFT A LETTER. "I DO NOT BELIEVE
THAT MY DREAM IS JUST AN ILLUSION…"
Where do you think they are right now?
It's the first case of your life.
Are you lamenting the fact
that you can't find them?
No. Humans can adapt to many things.
As long as they live a good life
where they are right now.
It's good. Very thorough.
I wouldn't have been able
to word it so vividly.
Of course. I'm your mentor after all.
Mr. He Yuanhang.
Humility is often a virtue.
Mr. Ran Fangxu.
Humility in excess is arrogance.
WRITTEN BY: RAN FANGXU, HE YUANHANG
TIME: JULY 5TH, 1997
-What's wrong?
-The name sequence is wrong.
No need for that.
-He.
-It's fine.
We must be truthful.
I am being truthful. Listen.
Investigation-wise,
you are the main contributor
who solved this case.
And in terms of your career,
you will stay in the criminal department.
Whereas I will return
to the police station.
-The sequence of our names
-Sir.
-does not matter.
Let me finish. It does not matter.
Tomorrow, I'll take the evaluation
report Captain Feng gives me
and return to the police station.
I want to show Qu Dahai just how…
-Why didn't you tell me?
-I tried.
-What did you say?
-Sir.
My wife is like this.
She gets angry very fast,
but she also forgets about it very fast.
She'll be fine in a few days.
He.
Have you ever considered staying?
Of course I have.
Why didn't you wait for me?
I want to see Uncle Ran off too.
Naughty girl! The floor is cold.
You came out without shoes.
Wear your shoes. Come.
You're here anyway.
Why should I wear my shoes?
Look at you. Your soles are dirty.
When mom sees that, she'll scold you.
Wash your feet when you go back.
Okay. You have to teach me
the 10th move of the evil-subduing
fist technique tonight.
Of course.
You see.
I don't have a huge ambition.
I understand.
He.
This isn't half bad either.
Come. Let's see Uncle Ran off.
Uncle Ran. Let me sing you a song.
My class sings this song when someone
-is transferring to another school.
-Sure.
Traveling the world
The journey
Is endless
Lost and aimless
One village after another
Staring at the setting sun
Sinking
And rising again
The world
Remains unchanged
The time remains long
You came all the way to Weiyang.
And those old things in the bureau
won't even come to send you off.
They are so heartless.
Sir. They have work to do.
They are in the special task force.
WEIYANG STATION
We're here.
Xiaohe. Let me speak
to Uncle Ran privately.
Have you ever considered staying?
WEIYANG
Maybe next time.
I should go now.
Xiaohe. I'm leaving now.
She doesn't want you to leave either.
But she's stubborn.
She won't show it.
Sir.
Take care.
Why did you leave so soon?
You heartless creature.
You won't even let me finish
what I want to say.
Are you scolding the train or me? Sir.
You decided to stay?
Sir,
you're right.
I cannot run away from it forever.
I'm staying to investigate
the June 30th case with you.
You finally got it through
your thick head.
I knew it. All these years in Beijing
and you still care about this case. Right?
Given your old age,
without my assistance,
you probably
won't be able to find anything.
Good boy.
You still care about me, after all.
Xiaohe. Look.
Guess who's back?
Look. This is my apprentice.
Ran Fangxu.
When we work together, we are invincible.
Peculiar cases or cold cases,
they are nothing to us.
Let alone a tiny Yuanlongli case. Right?
He's my apprentice.
My apprentice.
Wait.
I'm sure you've never left.
When Mrs. Feng's grandson,
Ma Qiang's nephew,
and Li Tieling's son
went missing in Yuanlongli,
you helped me locate them.
Sir. You got it wrong.
I've been teaching in Beijing.
This doesn't make sense.
The train had already departed.
You took the train and left
a long time ago.
How did you return?
How did the train return?